Jeremiah Snow

Software Developer Seattle, WA

linkedin.com/jlsnow301 | jlsnow.301@gmail.com | github portfolio | 206-379-0109

Summary

Communicative, pragmatic software developer with a focus on web and mobile development. A lifetime learner and avid code hobbyist with large contributions to open-source projects.

Soft Skills	Hard Skills
Detailed feedback	JavaScript: Expert.
Highly responsive	React: Expert.
Passionate code	Go: Intermediate.

Tech Stack

| TypeScript | Rust | Go | Python | Java | React | Vue | Astro | NextJS | NodeJS | Deno | CSS | HTML5 | Prisma | PlanetScale | Postgres | MySQL | MongoDB | Docker | AWS | GCP | Azure | UI | UX | Git |

Professional Experience

Software Developer

Aug 2022 - Present

Pareto Cyber

Remote

- In an Agile environment, worked closely with stakeholders to implement suggestions, build new features, demonstrate UI functionality.
- Using modern architecture, implemented tools to reduce build times by 97%.
- Refactored routing and state management, leading to a 36-point increase in Lighthouse performance score via Chrome dev tools.
- Pioneered converting the web application into TypeScript for reliable user experiences.
- Mentored coworkers on React and TypeScript fundamentals.
- Learned Postgres fundamentals and implemented secure, efficient data handling.
- Tech stack: React frontend, Go backend, Postgres DB, AWS cloud architecture.

Maintainer / Senior Developer

March 2020 - Present

TG Station

Remote

- Performed code reviews in an open-source GitHub repository which averages 120 new pull requests per week from 1,197 contributors.
- Collaborated with industry professionals to create beautifully designed user experiences.
- Individually replaced 477 user-facing dialogs with secure, feature loaded alternatives.
- Authored thorough documentation for every implemented feature and refactor.
- Tech stack: TypeScript React using the Inferno framework. DM backend, a C-relative language.

Projects

Lead Developer at Table Constructor

December 2022 - Present

- Built a complex React component using TypeScript using multiple industry standard libraries to dynamically generate data grids with type safe forms.
- Performs table virtualization when necessary to ensure high performance and cohesive user experiences even with large volumes of data.
- Exceedingly simple to use and well documented, allowing developers to quickly scaffold pages that display and edit data.

Full Stack Engineer at Financier

April 2021 - September 2021

- Implemented a proprietary algorithm designed by finance industry professionals to create a modern approach to risk management.
- Working with a small team, built a secure fintech application using Plaid API.
- Tech stack: JavaScript React frontend, NodeJS backend, Mongo database.

React Native Engineer at Ambient Noise

March 2020 - March 2021

- Researched and implemented APIs to develop a React Native mobile app that provided audio tours for prospective buyers.
- Implemented audio sampling to capture nearby road noises and more, aimed at providing prospective buyers with additional dimensions of data for their purchase.
- Quickly scaffolded a React Native project for stakeholders using Expo and Google Firebase.
- Wireframed and demonstrated UI functionality to a Zillow team for prototyping.
- Integrated secure cloud hosting and authentication.

Education

MS Information Technology Administration & Management

Central Washington University 4.0 GPA

2022 - Present

BAS Application Development

Seattle Colleges3.4 GPA

Graduate

AAS Computer Networking

Belmont College
3.7 GPA

2016 – 2018
Graduate

Interests & Hobbies

- Learning new languages spoken and machine.
- Web development, tech conferences, and new technology.
- Concerts, local music, and local art.
- Science fiction literature and movies.